After setting out to establish
a route to Shiganshina,
the Scout Regiment encountered
an intelligent, female Titan.
As soldier after soldier fell,
the regiment rushed
into a forest of giant trees,
much to everyone's puzzlement.
Who can possibly stop it,
if not the Levi Squad?!
Another one's dead!
We could've saved him, too!
Choose.
Will you trust yourself,
or me, these guys,
and the entire Scout Regiment?
I'll go with you!
Fire!
You don't mean...?!
They're going to take that Titan alive?!
What do you think of that, Eren?!
We caught that Titan!
This is the might of the Scout Regiment!
Don't underrate us, you idiot!
Now do you see?!
Yes!
It looks like she's stopped.
We can't drop our guard yet.
I'm just impressed you
managed to lead her to this spot.
The credit goes to the rear squad
members who gave their lives fighting her.
They bought us time.
It would've been impossible otherwise.
Is that so?
Yes.
Thanks to them...
...we get to see who's
inside this one's nape.
Let's just hope they're not
wetting themself inside there...
I won't let your deaths be meaningless
even if I'm the last one standing
In both hands, Gloria
What sings is Sieg
On my back, Flügel der Freiheit
Clenched determination to my left chest
What slashes across is Linie der Torheit
Soaring across the azure skies
Flügel der Freiheit
"Erwin Smith"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 4"
An Abnormal...
Or is it like the Colossal Titan?
Wait, did Commander Erwin actually--?
Hey! Quit spacin' out!
Eren!
You can think later!
We need to get further ahead!
Right!
Wait, Levi.
We need to be extra cautious.
Waves 2 and 3!
Fire!
Use the reserves too!
Umm, they're starting to climb up...
Indeed.
If they make it up this far,
perhaps I'll step out of the way.
Although...
I suspect we'll soon be given
orders to withdraw anyway.
Does it have something to do
with those explosions inside the forest?
I don't know.
Mikasa...
What do you think those sounds are?
Are cannons being
fired inside the forest?
I didn't see them bring
any cannons in, though...
What's with all this damn noise?
Hey, Mr. Bertholdt.
Do you know which way Christa went?
Sorry. I don't.
Nothing makes sense anymore.
What are we even doing now, and why?
I wanna go home...
--Let's move away, Armin!
--Right!
Looks like the bastard's
gotten the hang of it.
It's gotten better and
better at tree-climbing!
The scary thing is that
this means they can learn.
Although I'm sure it's
different for each Titan too.
Armin.
They seem to be up to
something inside the forest,
and I think I've
figured out what it is.
They lured that female Titan here
to capture her.
Or, more precisely,
to capture the human inside.
That was Commander Erwin's goal...
...from the very start.
Wasn't it?!
Still, I can understand keeping
it from us rookies, but you guys too?!
You've been Scouts a long time!
Man, you're annoying!
Are you suggesting the commander
and the captain don't trust us?!
N-No, but that's what
this means, doesn't it?!
Petra! Knock out his teeth!
Switch his front teeth with his back ones!
No, Eren's right.
The captain must've had a
reason for not trusting us implicitly.
Like what?
There's only one reason
he couldn't trust his comrades.
There's someone in the regiment
who can either turn into a Titan
or is working as a sort of spy for them.
You think so too, right?
That there's someone in the regiment...
Mm. I think there is.
A spy?
Are you really sure?
At the very least,
the commander must believe so.
I assume the only soldiers
informed of this operation
were the ones who survived five years ago.
I see.
So that's why...
Yep, that's gotta be it.
Get it, Eren?
That's what's goin' on.
Mm. In that case, it couldn't be helped.
Yeah...
Five years ago
was when the wall first fell...
Could they be using that
fact to narrow down suspects
on the assumption
that's when the spy got inside?
Does that mean this person
killed Sawney and Bean too?
The commander asked me
something after that happened...
What do you see here?
What do you think the enemy is?
Is that what that meant?
We might've been allowed
to join the operation
if we'd known the answer to that question.
I doubt any of us could have, though.
Well, I knew.
But I decided not to say anything.
Do you guys know why?
Why?
What, you mean you don't know?
I guess guys like
you wouldn't know, huh?
You're nowhere near my
level yet, after all.
Seriously, are you still
trying to imitate Captain Levi?
He doesn't talk like that.
If this succeeds, we might actually
learn the truth about this world.
Still, even for that...
...way too many people have died.
Do you think the commander
was wrong to do this?
He wasn't in the right,
I'll tell you that.
If we'd actually been told
that a Titan had inside info,
we would've handled things differently.
Your own squad members, for example...
--No, it wasn't wrong.
--Huh?
How can you say that?
Do you know how many
soldiers have needlessly died?!
Jean.
In hindsight, it's easy to
say what should've been done.
But...
No one can tell how things will turn out.
Yet, at some point
you have to make a choice.
The lives of a hundred comrades...
...or the lives of
everyone inside the walls.
The commander chose.
He chose to throw away
the lives of a hundred comrades.
Eren.
If you didn't know already,
you'll soon learn why
Erwin Smith was put in charge
of the Scouts, of humanity's hope...
It's why he even
has Captain Levi's trust!
That's assuming you
survive long enough, of course.
I don't have much
life experience yet...
...but I do know one thing.
If there's anyone who
can bring about change,
it's someone capable of
giving up what matters most.
In particular, people who are capable
of abandoning their humanity
when forced to rise above monsters.
Those who can't abandon anything...
...can't change anything.
Fire!
How do you like that?
Now you can't scratch a
single itch or move a single muscle.
And you probably never will again.
The more your wounds heal,
the stiffer your joints will get!
Still, why haven't they
extracted our esteemed guest yet?
What are Levi and Miche doing?!
So she has the ability to cover portions
of her body with hardened skin...
Much like the Armored Titan I've heard about.
Will it weaken if we continue
an ODM sword assault?
There's no time to try.
In which case...
Sir!
Prepare to blast it.
Blow off the target's hands.
Yes, Sir!
However, there's a
risk our standard artillery
could take out everything
on the inside as well.
Then let's attempt to
sever the wrists instead.
Fire an all-out salvo on my signal.
Understood!
Hey. Just come out already, will you?
We don't got time for this.
Say, what do you think's
gonna happen to you now?
Do you really think you
can get out of this situation?
I wish you'd pay some thought
to the trouble you've caused us.
You killed our men in
all sorts of different ways.
Was it fun?
Well, I'm having fun now.
I take it you're the same way.
If there's anyone who
knows how I feel, it's you.
Oh, right.
There's one thing I need to ask.
Will you be fine if
your limbs get cut off?
They'll go grow back, right?
I'm talking about your actual body.
Can't afford to have
you die on us, after all...
Damn. You startled me there.
Were those her death throes?
Erwin. I smell them.
Which direction?
All directions, all at once!
Lots of them!
What the...?!
They're rushing into the forest all at once!
Why are they suddenly ignoring us?!
What?!
Does this mean they're all Abnormals?!
Doesn't matter! Don't let 'em through!
Commence combat!
What was that all of a sudden?!
Please, wait!
I've heard screams like that before!
In the forest where I'm from!
It's the sound a cornered animal makes
when it's ready to give up everything!
I was taught the end of a hunt
is when you have to be most careful!
So you want me to be careful?
Please be a hundred times
more careful than normal!
You will die if you
don't take the forest seriously!
I'm from the mountains too, actually...
You're a vegetable farmer!
You wouldn't understand!
I see.
Sasha's hunches are often right.
And it's usually only before
something bad happens...
Armin said Eren might be in the
rear of the center rank, as I recall...
Hurry with artillery!
Erwin!
The first wave is coming
from the east! They're close!
Wagon defense squad! Intercept them!
They're ignoring us?!
Are they Abnormals?!
Three Titans have broken through!
Captain Levi!
Hey, you...
You just did something, didn't you?
It went for the female one?
Titans coming from all directions!
All soldiers, commence combat!
Defend the Female Titan at all costs!
No!
All soldiers, withdraw!
Redeploy the formation!
Return to Calaneth District!
We've been bested.
What's with that pathetic look of yours?
This goes to show that the enemy
was prepared to throw away everything.
I never imagined our target
would resort to Titan cannibalization
to dispose of information...
After all that blustering we did
in the courtroom, this is how it turns out...
If we waltz back there now,
who knows what'll happen to Eren or us...
We can think about that once we've returned.
For now, we need to focus on returning
without sustaining any further losses.
For now.
The steam is impairing visibility.
It could hinder smoke signal communications.
I'm going to get my squad.
Wait, Levi.
Replenish your gas and blades first.
We're low on time and
I have enough to last already.
Why?
That's an order. Do as you're told.
Whatever you say, Erwin.
I'll trust your judgment.
The withdrawal signal.
We're all to withdraw and
return to base on horseback.
Right!
What? Is it all over?
All right! We can go home!
Just what's going on?
Is Eren all right?
Looks like it's over.
Let's get back to the
horses! Prepare to withdraw!
You heard the man.
Let's go see what the
bastard riding inside it looks like.
Did they really find out who it is?
All thanks to you!
Huh? But I didn't do anything.
You trusted us, remember?
Things turned out this way
because you chose to stick with us.
Making the right call is a pretty
hard thing to do, you know!
Hey, now. Quit pamperin' him, Petra.
How was he any help?
All he did was whine
like a pathetic little brat.
I guess making it back alive might
be considered praiseworthy,
but only after the
mission's done and over with.
Just so you know, twerp, an expedition
ain't over 'til you're back home.
Yes, I get it already!
Oruo! Petra!
For a couple of soldiers who cried and
pissed their pants during their first battle,
you've really grown!
Don't mention that!
Are you trying to make
him lose respect for me, Eld?!
Whoa, she really did?!
It's the truth.
And, just so you know,
I never pissed myself, Eren.
You idiot! I'll have you know
I have the highest kill count!
I'm the best, you moron!
There's more to a soldier's
merits than just kill counts!
Shut up, you idiot!
Ms. Petra! Does that mean
it sprayed everywhere in midair?!
Knock it off!
Are you on a picnic or something?!
We're outside the walls, you know!
Also, I never wet myself either, Eren!
Oh. That must be a
message from Captain Levi.
We're rendezvousing with the captain!
Stow the chatter until we're home!
Erwin.
Why did you have
Levi replenish his supplies
when there's no time to waste?
The female was eaten.
But did you see the
person inside get eaten?
I didn't.
Are you saying...?!
Yes.
If, as you deduced earlier,
we're dealing with a type that remains
able-bodied after de-transformation...
And, if said person had equipped
themselves with ODM gear in advance...
...that means they're now
wearing one of our uniforms...
Captain Levi?
No... It's not!
Who are you?!
M-Mr. Gunther!
Hey! Why...?!
Mr. Gunther!
...and have blended in
with the rest of us soldiers.
If, by chance, I'm not me
then who's to say that you're you?
Can you pick up the pieces of your heart
that fell apart like a broken sand castle?
The voice of someone calling out
changed into ringing in my ears
It's as if time has stopped
Now wake up
I made my way out of the deep darkness
I fled like a swift wind
We used to be like living corpses,
but now we head beyond the walls
Let's meet again
in a place not on any map
The capture operation has failed.
The Female Titan appears
before Eren once more.
Standing in the way is a
team of Titan-killing experts...
...the Special Operations Squad.
"Crushing Blow"
"The 57th Exterior Scouting Mission, Part 5"